<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>frontend on Thomas Wilson</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/tags/frontend/</link><description>Recent content in frontend on Thomas Wilson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>© Thomas Wilson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thomaswilson.xyz/tags/frontend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I don't want to be a unicorn 🦄, an engineer or a designer - I just want to build things better</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-05-31-unicorns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-05-31-unicorns/</guid><description>I like building software, or parts of software, which are visual and interactive. I do not particularly enjoy the more abstract, very important, areas like technical optimisation, language design, or anything with the word &amp;ldquo;distributed&amp;rdquo; in it. I like building user interfaces (UIs); but also architecting and engineering the code that underlies these interfaces, so that engineers can build delightful and functional UIs, without going through as much effort. Good UI and user experience (UX) should be a norm, a default.</description></item><item><title>What is CSS-in-JS and why do people keep using it?</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/what-and-why-use-css-in-js/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/what-and-why-use-css-in-js/</guid><description>The elders tell us of a time where you would build websites by literally writing your .html files. If you wanted to add some styles, you’d write them in a .css file and then &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot;&amp;gt; the two together. So you’d write your entire site in semantic HTML, about whatever it is people did back then (like mammoth hunting or pyramid building) and then you would ftp that onto your server, and other people could view it.</description></item></channel></rss>