<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>non-fiction on Thomas Wilson</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/tags/non-fiction/</link><description>Recent content in non-fiction on Thomas Wilson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>© Thomas Wilson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thomaswilson.xyz/tags/non-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>After</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/after/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/after/</guid><description>Declaration of interest I am a spiritual person. I didn’t come into this book desperately seeking answers, or in need of comfort or certainty. You’re never going to get that from any book, I’m afraid. I believe that we are not just our bodies, and that consciousness exists (at least partially) separately to the brain. I came into this book because I was interested in hearing the experiences of a healthcare and scientific professional, and how they experience / grapple with these questions.</description></item><item><title>First You Write a Sentence</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/first-you-write-a-sentence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/first-you-write-a-sentence/</guid><description>I loved this book. Will love this book again, because I know I&amp;rsquo;m going to read it again. And then probably again after that. Moran&amp;rsquo;s two hundred page treatise on the process of writing and re-writing is meatier than you would expect. Every few pages serve you a meal, a new way to think about reading or writing: how active is the voice? Remember punctuation? Does this make sense? Moran shows you the importance of these questions, and the consequences of (not) adhering to them.</description></item><item><title>The Phoenix Project</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/the-phoenix-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/the-phoenix-project/</guid><description>The Phoenix Project (TPP) is a a fiction book for nerds (said the nerd, on his blog). It&amp;rsquo;s a parable for people who design, build, or deploy software. I want this article to just be about the book itself, not its content. The things I, as an engineer, found interesting about The Phoenix Project deserve their own post. Instead, this piece takes a more literary, or meta, look at The Phoenix Project.</description></item><item><title>On Connection</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/on-connection/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/on-connection/</guid><description>Kae Tempest is a London-based artist who works with words. I first discovered their work in 2016, with the release of Let Them Eat Chaos - a conceptual spoken word album which imagines a London street at 4:18am. To be perfectly honestly I think Tempest has a well honed skill with words. Their work has spoken to me with clarity in times when not a lot else could get through. Some of Tempest&amp;rsquo;s phrases and lyrics are burned, deep, into my brain and emerge with remarkable frequency when I&amp;rsquo;m just trying to live my life.</description></item><item><title>how do we know we're doing it right?</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/how-do-we-know-were-doing-it-right/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/how-do-we-know-were-doing-it-right/</guid><description>Sykes' collection of essays covers a surprisingly large amount of ground for a relatively short book. She turns her attention to a lot of the inner turmoils that seem to plague millennials' inner monologues, as well as broader societal issues: fast fashion, the &amp;ldquo;true self&amp;rdquo;, instagram husbands, and work-life balance all feature. How do we know we&amp;rsquo;re doing it right? clearly comes from a lot of careful conversations, introspection, and research but at times Sykes seems to lose herself under disjointed quotations of other peoples' words.</description></item><item><title>wow, no thank you</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/wow-no-thank-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/wow-no-thank-you/</guid><description>Samantha Irby came onto my radar in 2019 after a reading slump from that time I was burned out by my job in a VC startup. We are never meeting in real life, her previous set of essays published in 2017, was displayed prominently in a central London bookstore it was a) bright yellow, and b) covered in a picture of a hateful cat - so I started believing in destiny and bought the book, read the book, and adored it.</description></item></channel></rss>