<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>react on Thomas Wilson</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/tags/react/</link><description>Recent content in react on Thomas Wilson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>© Thomas Wilson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thomaswilson.xyz/tags/react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I chose React Native to build a new app in 2020</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-03-22-why-i-chose-react-native-for-app-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-03-22-why-i-chose-react-native-for-app-in-2020/</guid><description>I am currently in the process of building herabouts - an app that’s like a tour guide, only cooler. Most of my previous engineering work has been web-based (react and vue) because the internet is an accessible and very capable system for building modern applications. However hereabouts needed certain native functionality - like location, reliable offline data access, battery status, and access to the camera. Yes some of these things are possible on the web, but they’re much more native functionality.</description></item><item><title>Moving my personal site to Gatsby</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/moving-from-nuxt-to-gatsbyjs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/moving-from-nuxt-to-gatsbyjs/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I was having a conversation with someone about modern web design, and we spoke about web fonts and variable fonts. In my experience, people who work in software development have a couple of hills that they will die on, if so required. For this person - the idea of not using system fonts (i.e. typefaces which are already installed on a user’s device) was completely baffling. Why are we increasing the time-to-load and packet size required to display a web page - just for a typeface.</description></item></channel></rss>