<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All Book Reviews on Thomas Wilson</title>
    <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All Book Reviews on Thomas Wilson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>© Thomas Wilson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sistersong</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/sistersong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/sistersong/</guid>
      <description>Sistersong is the debut novel from Lucy Holland. Set in Dumnonia, the Celtic kingdom which lasted between the 4th-8th century in what is now South West England, it follows the three children of the king (introduced as Riva, Synne, and Keyne), as they come of age and start to see the word “as it is”.
The world now is far from the one the siblings grew up in. Threatened by the surrounding Saxons, losing connection to the land’s magic, and waining religious beliefs all give this book an excellent backdrop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Hail Mary</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/project-hail-mary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/project-hail-mary/</guid>
      <description>When you read a Dan Brown book you leave it ready to put on your tin foil har. Andy Weir books make you feel ready to don a lab coat. He writes books that are clearly well researched and very involved, but they’re still readable. Dan Brown gets (at most) one of these two things.
Project Hail Mary is inevitably going to be compared to Weir’s 2011 The Martian, a book which received (well deserved) critical and public acclaim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hangover Square</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/hangover-square/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/hangover-square/</guid>
      <description>I was gifted this book by my mother, so I feel terrible for what I am about to say about it. It was gifted with the best of intentions: someone or other famous reported that it made them feel at home in London, a city I love. But a city that can feel indifferent to you. This book did not make me feel at home in this city. It showed how it is possible for a place to be the centre of art, politics, ambition and still allow anyone to shift un-affixed through their life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/after/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/after/</guid>
      <description>Declaration of interest I am a spiritual person. I didn’t come into this book desperately seeking answers, or in need of comfort or certainty. You’re never going to get that from any book, I’m afraid. I believe that we are not just our bodies, and that consciousness exists (at least partially) separately to the brain. I came into this book because I was interested in hearing the experiences of a healthcare and scientific professional, and how they experience / grapple with these questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs Death Misses Death</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/mrs-death-misses-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/mrs-death-misses-death/</guid>
      <description>Godden has been writing and performing poetry since she decided to move to London instead of going to university. “Godden is a poet” headlines my review because it is so evident in every page of this book. Every transition from unknown narrator, to fourth-wall breaking direct address, to poetry, to “normal” prose. Godden barely pays attention to consistency when she writes, because she is trying to get across an idea. All books are poor transcriptions of spoken word stories that buoyed humanity through tens of thousands of years, long before we invented written word, paper, and typesetting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Once Upon a River</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/once-upon-a-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/once-upon-a-river/</guid>
      <description>This is a lovely book where classically fairy tale things happen. Set on the River Thames in Oxford around the turn of the 20th century, it follows individuals and families as a girl is found not-quite-dead in the river. Everybody sees somebody different in this child, they see the lost daughter they wished they could re-find, or the lost sibling who died some thirty years ago. We follow the people of the village as they attempt to care for, claim stewardship over, and make counter-claims about her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magician</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/magician/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/magician/</guid>
      <description>The first in Feist&amp;rsquo;s Riftwar Saga, Magician has the air of a pulp fantasy novel. First published, abridged, in 1982 and unabridged a decade later, this book oozes nerds in the &amp;rsquo;70s playing D&amp;amp;D and I love that. It has it&amp;rsquo;s bona fides as a fantasy novel and that&amp;rsquo;s what made me pick it up in the first place. Unfortunately, I could never find myself truly getting into Magician in a way that I have with more contemporary fantasy series (like Brent Week&amp;rsquo;s Lightbringer, or Peter V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utopia Avenue</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/utopia-avenue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/utopia-avenue/</guid>
      <description>Utopia Avenue is David Mitchell&amp;rsquo;s latest piece of fiction in the meta-novel he is writing. Which is to say this book is set in the same mild-fantasy universe as several of his others. It follows the motley crew of musicians and management which form the titular rock/folk/pop band in London in 1967, including cameos from near every famous London-based musician of the time. I&amp;rsquo;ve no strong attachment to the era or to early rock-n-roll music and the book never relied on nostalgia or knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First You Write a Sentence</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/first-you-write-a-sentence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/first-you-write-a-sentence/</guid>
      <description>I loved this book. Will love this book again, because I know I&amp;rsquo;m going to read it again. And then probably again after that. Moran&amp;rsquo;s two hundred page treatise on the process of writing and re-writing is meatier than you would expect. Every few pages serve you a meal, a new way to think about reading or writing: how active is the voice? Remember punctuation? Does this make sense? Moran shows you the importance of these questions, and the consequences of (not) adhering to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Silence of the Girls</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/the-silence-of-the-girls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/the-silence-of-the-girls/</guid>
      <description>Pat Barker&amp;rsquo;s take on the classic story of the Battle of Troy is told from the perspective of Briseis, the noble taken slave when Achilles sacks Lyrnessus. Consigned to life as a bed slave for Achilles, she is later taken from Achilles by Agamemnon, which in turn causes Achilles to stop fighting for the Greeks. In the tradition of classic epic poems like the Iliad, women and slaves are treated entirely as property - not as humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kings of the Wyld</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/kings-of-the-wyld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/kings-of-the-wyld/</guid>
      <description>Kings of the Wyld is a fantasy book which feels like three or four middle (or-upper middle) aged dudes getting drunk, playing Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons, while classic Rock and Roll plays in the background. In a fantasy world where adventurers are treated like rockstars, the book follows an old band of adventures getting together for one last hurrah to save one of their daughters. The book knows what it is, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to overreach itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Phoenix Project</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/the-phoenix-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/the-phoenix-project/</guid>
      <description>The Phoenix Project (TPP) is a a fiction book for nerds (said the nerd, on his blog). It&amp;rsquo;s a parable for people who design, build, or deploy software. I want this article to just be about the book itself, not its content. The things I, as an engineer, found interesting about The Phoenix Project deserve their own post. Instead, this piece takes a more literary, or meta, look at The Phoenix Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Connection</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/on-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/on-connection/</guid>
      <description>Kae Tempest is a London-based artist who works with words. I first discovered their work in 2016, with the release of Let Them Eat Chaos - a conceptual spoken word album which imagines a London street at 4:18am. To be perfectly honestly I think Tempest has a well honed skill with words. Their work has spoken to me with clarity in times when not a lot else could get through. Some of Tempest&amp;rsquo;s phrases and lyrics are burned, deep, into my brain and emerge with remarkable frequency when I&amp;rsquo;m just trying to live my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Absolutely Remarkable Thing</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/an-absolutely-remarkable-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/an-absolutely-remarkable-thing/</guid>
      <description>An Absolutely Remarkable Thing (AART; because I&amp;rsquo;m not paid by the word here) is a wonderful Sci-Fi(-ish) adventure by Hank Green, one of the content creators in the first wave of the YouTube-meets-mainstream movement. It&amp;rsquo;s a delightful first piece in his The Carls series, and even if the characters fall a little flat - the story is compelling enough to make this book a delightful and worthy read. Green&amp;rsquo;s obviously got a lot to say about the current state of internet, fame, media, and global attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamnet</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/hamnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/hamnet/</guid>
      <description>Hamnet follows Agnes, the wife of William Shakespeare, and her family - her brothers, children, in-laws - as well as several of the greater village populous. The book makes very few references to William, and never actually names him. He is always &amp;ldquo;he&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;husband&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;father&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;him&amp;rdquo;. Describing Agnes as &amp;ldquo;the wife&amp;rdquo;, as I did mere sentences ago, serves only as an introduction, and as a drastic under-selling of Agnes.
Set in a 1500s southern England, the book darts between the characters&#39; present - following the life and early death of Hamnet, Agnes&#39; only son - and the years preceding these events: Agnes&#39; childhood, meeting her husband, raising a family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cat&#39;s Cradle</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/cats-cradle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/cats-cradle/</guid>
      <description>After Slaughterhouse 5, Cat&amp;rsquo;s Cradle is the second Vonnegut book I&amp;rsquo;ve read. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard wonderful things about Vonnegut, and this book exemplifies a lot of those, namely uncomfortable observations and a black, dry humour. The book circles a number of themes, principally the dangers of purely objective or impersonal scientific research, and the role of religion to society and people. It hits these notes well throughout the piece, but I found the meandering, seemingly powerless, plot arch a little unstable at times - like there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything for me to reliably hold on to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queenie</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/queenie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/queenie/</guid>
      <description>Queenie is an excellent debut by Carty-William. The novel&amp;rsquo;s titular narrator pins you to the page - she has a strong and unique voice, yet also unreliable and unlikable at times. It takes you through something which feels both personal and also cultural: micro-aggressions, personal and collective trauma, mental health, and love and friendship in the early 21st century. It&amp;rsquo;s a really gripping and motivating work that Carty-Williams manages to end on a hopeful, if a little well-trodden, note.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how do we know we&#39;re doing it right?</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/how-do-we-know-were-doing-it-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/how-do-we-know-were-doing-it-right/</guid>
      <description>Sykes&#39; collection of essays covers a surprisingly large amount of ground for a relatively short book. She turns her attention to a lot of the inner turmoils that seem to plague millennials&#39; inner monologues, as well as broader societal issues: fast fashion, the &amp;ldquo;true self&amp;rdquo;, instagram husbands, and work-life balance all feature. How do we know we&amp;rsquo;re doing it right? clearly comes from a lot of careful conversations, introspection, and research but at times Sykes seems to lose herself under disjointed quotations of other peoples&#39; words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wow, no thank you</title>
      <link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/wow-no-thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/wow-no-thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Samantha Irby came onto my radar in 2019 after a reading slump from that time I was burned out by my job in a VC startup. We are never meeting in real life, her previous set of essays published in 2017, was displayed prominently in a central London bookstore it was a) bright yellow, and b) covered in a picture of a hateful cat - so I started believing in destiny and bought the book, read the book, and adored it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
