<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fantasy on Thomas Wilson</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/tags/fantasy/</link><description>Recent content in fantasy on Thomas Wilson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>© Thomas Wilson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/tags/fantasy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sistersong</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/sistersong/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/sistersong/</guid><description>Sistersong is the debut novel from Lucy Holland. Set in Dumnonia, the Celtic kingdom which lasted between the 4th-8th century in what is now South West England, it follows the three children of the king (introduced as Riva, Synne, and Keyne), as they come of age and start to see the word “as it is”.
The world now is far from the one the siblings grew up in. Threatened by the surrounding Saxons, losing connection to the land’s magic, and waining religious beliefs all give this book an excellent backdrop.</description></item><item><title>Magician</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/magician/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/magician/</guid><description>The first in Feist&amp;rsquo;s Riftwar Saga, Magician has the air of a pulp fantasy novel. First published, abridged, in 1982 and unabridged a decade later, this book oozes nerds in the &amp;rsquo;70s playing D&amp;amp;D and I love that. It has it&amp;rsquo;s bona fides as a fantasy novel and that&amp;rsquo;s what made me pick it up in the first place. Unfortunately, I could never find myself truly getting into Magician in a way that I have with more contemporary fantasy series (like Brent Week&amp;rsquo;s Lightbringer, or Peter V.</description></item><item><title>Utopia Avenue</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/utopia-avenue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/utopia-avenue/</guid><description>Utopia Avenue is David Mitchell&amp;rsquo;s latest piece of fiction in the meta-novel he is writing. Which is to say this book is set in the same mild-fantasy universe as several of his others. It follows the motley crew of musicians and management which form the titular rock/folk/pop band in London in 1967, including cameos from near every famous London-based musician of the time. I&amp;rsquo;ve no strong attachment to the era or to early rock-n-roll music and the book never relied on nostalgia or knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Kings of the Wyld</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/kings-of-the-wyld/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/book-reviews/kings-of-the-wyld/</guid><description>Kings of the Wyld is a fantasy book which feels like three or four middle (or-upper middle) aged dudes getting drunk, playing Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons, while classic Rock and Roll plays in the background. In a fantasy world where adventurers are treated like rockstars, the book follows an old band of adventures getting together for one last hurrah to save one of their daughters. The book knows what it is, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to overreach itself.</description></item></channel></rss>