<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hereabouts on Thomas Wilson</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/tags/hereabouts/</link><description>Recent content in hereabouts on Thomas Wilson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>© Thomas Wilson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/tags/hereabouts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hereabouts devblog #2 - March 2020</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-04-02-hereabouts-devblog-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-04-02-hereabouts-devblog-2/</guid><description>Hi, I’m Thomas Wilson, I’m a web and mobile engineer building Hereabouts - an app that’s like a tour guide if the tour guide was like Roman Mars after three beers. This is a devblog where I talk about my progress building that app. Also I’m very sorry, Roman, you’re one of a handful of people who I genuinely aspire to be like please don’t take me seriously.
Well March 2020 has certainly turned out to be quite the introduction to working on a side project.</description></item><item><title>Hereabouts devblog #1</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-02-24-hereabouts-devblog-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-02-24-hereabouts-devblog-1/</guid><description>Hi, my name’s Thomas Wilson but I often go by my just my surname. I’m 28 years old, currently based in London, England, and I design and build software for a living through my small independent studio tinyfox studio. At the beginning of 2020 I quit my job to do this independently, and now I’m building hereabouts - an app that provides self-paced walks, tours, hunts, and races for travel adventurers In this devblog series I want to record to the process of building something modern and beautiful from the ground up.</description></item></channel></rss>