<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>figma on Thomas Wilson</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/tags/figma/</link><description>Recent content in figma on Thomas Wilson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>© Thomas Wilson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thomaswilson.xyz/tags/figma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing Figma Variants with 5 Components that aren't Buttons</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-19-figma-variants-without-buttons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-19-figma-variants-without-buttons/</guid><description>Figma recently introduced Variants - a way of extending and varying your components. Components in Figma, and in modern web development, are reusable and encapsulated elements of a design - with the classic examples of a Button or a Card.
Variants add new flexibility, and utility, to components in Figma by introducing properties and values to them in a programmatic way. If you have experience writing modern web applications, these variants and properties are like a specific subset of props which you pass to a component.</description></item><item><title>Kickstarting UX Design with ugly working documents: Screens, Components, Actions, and State.</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-03-15-ugly-but-functional-ux-design/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-03-15-ugly-but-functional-ux-design/</guid><description>UX design resists standardisation or templates. It can’t be a one-size-fits-all approach, and the nature of the product, audience, and production team all mean that something different is needed each time. Whenever I get past the early stages of UX design (like understanding what a product does, and who it does it for) - I find myself with a different working document and process than I’ve needed before.
I wanted to share the things I do that give me the momentum to get to a place where I can do this more specific kind of document.</description></item></channel></rss>