<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>All Posts on Thomas Wilson</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/</link><description>Recent content in All Posts on Thomas Wilson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>© Thomas Wilson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 18:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>It feels like the handbrake has come off</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-10-25-the-handbrake-has-come-off/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-10-25-the-handbrake-has-come-off/</guid><description>Over the past two months I have inherited leadership of an engineering team I have worked in for the last twelve months. In the last two weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the speed of development go from not-slow, to almost inarguably fast (given current resource constraints).
I&amp;rsquo;ve spent months slowly attempting to unpick the parts of the team and company which were bottlenecks. There&amp;rsquo;s actually some very interesting conversations around what makes a bottleneck, and how do you spot one.</description></item><item><title>Back in office: summer 2021</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-10-11-back-in-office/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 07:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-10-11-back-in-office/</guid><description>After a year and a half of very new normal, summer 2021 was pretty perfect. I mean, the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t summery, being around a lot of strangers (and even friends) felt odd, and there seemed an awful lot of pressure to make this The Best Summer Ever.
I&amp;rsquo;m pretty grateful for a lot of small moments this summer.
Here are some of those moments:
Moved to Oxford and filled a moderate-sized house with an unwise number of plants Climbed Helvellyn and Haystacks in the Lake District Ate food outside with friends Ate food inside with family Watched campfires Drank gin on hot evenings and cold nights from between clinking ice and wedges of citrus Cycled through sunny mornings and afternoons</description></item><item><title>Out of office: summer 2021</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-07-08-out-of-office/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-07-08-out-of-office/</guid><description>Summer has always been a time for doing and living. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right to force at least one piece of writing out of my brain every week. Discipline and routine are useful tools for living, but so is taking a summer break. I&amp;rsquo;m going out of office for the next couple of months, so I can focus on the latter. I want long cycles, solitary train rides, food eaten outdoors, and adventure.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #45: This is an old story</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-27-weekly-45-this-is-an-old-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 08:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-27-weekly-45-this-is-an-old-story/</guid><description>The Weekly is a series of essays where I write on something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about over the last seven days. They&amp;rsquo;re under a thousand words. There&amp;rsquo;s some stuff going on in my professional life (positive stuff, but still stuff, you know?) so it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a short one this week. It&amp;rsquo;s better to publish than not.
I want to talk about old stories. I mean things that people have been experiencing for thousands or tens or thousands of years.</description></item><item><title>The infinite coast of problem solving</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-13-infinite-coast-of-problem-solving/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-13-infinite-coast-of-problem-solving/</guid><description>I’m currently designing and building the lexicon, ambitiously explained as “the most useful language learning resources in the world”.
The problem is that there’s a lot involved in that, you know? There’s theoretical questions like “what does most useful mean?” and “how do humans learn languages”?
Then there’s small problems like “what is the shape of the JSON I send to the client?” and “how do I generate prompts &amp;amp; questions for language learning?</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #44: Thinking about Conspiracy Theories</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-10-weekly-44-thinking-about-conspiracy-theories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-10-weekly-44-thinking-about-conspiracy-theories/</guid><description>The Weekly is a series of essays under one thousand words where I write about something I’ve been thinking over the last seven days. This week I want to talk about misinformation and conspiracy theories surrounding Covid-19, and why they’re more harmful than previous conspiracy theories. I’ve been a little busier than usual this week, so let’s get into it
Alongside the actual pandemic of Covid-19, the World Health Organisation (WHO) has declared an infodemic: the “false or misleading information in digital and physical environments during a disease outbreak”.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #43: Vision, problem, and action</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-05-weekly-43-vision-problem-action/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 10:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-05-weekly-43-vision-problem-action/</guid><description>The Weekly is a weekly essay where I write about something I’ve been thinking about in the last seven days. They’re under 1000 words, and this week I want to talk about vision and problems when you’re building a new product.
I’m building the lexicon, where I am (un-ironically) trying to build the world’s most useful language learning resources. I like Duo Lingo, but I don’t think it helps you much in the real world ™️.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #42: Metaphors for Design - Brutalist Architecture, Gardens, and Video Games</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-28-the-weekly-42-metaphors-for-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-28-the-weekly-42-metaphors-for-design/</guid><description>The Weekly is a weekly essay on something I’ve been thinking about in the last seven days. They’re less than a thousand words long. This week I want to talk about the metaphors we use when we talk about designing for the web.
I read two (fantastic) pieces on the web this week:
What even is a website anyway? by Manuel Moreale, who cited, Brutalist Web Design by Carl Barenbrug Sometimes I have no time for Medium-style self proclaimed “think pieces” about the web and technology.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #41: Productivity is a daily ritual</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-21-productivity-is-a-daily-ritual/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 20:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-21-productivity-is-a-daily-ritual/</guid><description>The Weekly is a 1000-word-or-less essay on something I’ve been thinking this week. Let’s talk about how productivity is (basically) a scam and how daily and weekly rituals are the backbone of any sane person&amp;rsquo;s productivity.
I once had the goal to move to Paris. I didn’t achieve it (there was a pandemic). I had a goal to learn Italian (laziness). We’ve all got visions of our future where we’re cleverer, skinnier, more intelligent, or in my case simply the same person but somewhere else.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #40: Garlic &amp; The Ancients</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-15-weekly-40/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-15-weekly-40/</guid><description>Okay let’s learn us how over the past 3000 years garlic has been espoused by healers and spiritual leaders to ward off disease and evil. It’ll take you down a rabbit hole of medical advice, social segregation, and spiritual prohibition.
Garlic (Allium Sativum, of theAllium genus) has set its roots deep in the human story. And let’s get one thing straight: garlic is bloody great. It’s scientifically categorised in a group of foods called “please don’t take these away from me”.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #39 (or #1, whatever)</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-06-weekly-39/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-06-weekly-39/</guid><description>I’m going to stop writing my “things I learned” blog posts. They don’t serve me in the way that they used to. As I wrote recently: kill your ideas and side projects, gladly and without delay.
Death is more of a transition, though. The things I learned this week post is becoming simply _The Weekly.
I’m not sure what I’m going to use it to write about, I’m going to take a few weeks to try some new formats out.</description></item><item><title>[LinkedIn Post] Being so customer-centric your customers think you’re a robot</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-05-customer-centric-like-a-robot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-05-customer-centric-like-a-robot/</guid><description>(This is a cross-post of a short article I wrote on LinkedIn)
Stop me if you’ve heard any of these: “your call is valuable to us”… “on a scale of 1-10 how would you rate our…”, ”at {companyName} we care deeply about our customer experience…”
Have you literally ever believed anybody when you’ve heard or read these things? I have not. Not even once.
But we should care. I know Oxwash does.</description></item><item><title>(Not) Things I learned this week #38</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-01-things-i-learned-38/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-01-things-i-learned-38/</guid><description>(Not) Things I learned this week #38 This week seems to have really flown by. I’ve decided to take purposeful and intentional time for rest and personal recuperation this week. I’m not feeling burned out, but I could certainly smell some distant smoke on the wind. So here’s to taking evenings to get around to those household repairs I’ve been putting off, to that growing pile of unread books. I said 2021 was my Year of Discourse and as we transition from winter to spring, I’m checking in with myself.</description></item><item><title>Excommunicate your ideas</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-27-excommunicate-your-ideas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-27-excommunicate-your-ideas/</guid><description>Your side-projects deserve a decisive, merciful death at your hands. You dragged them into this world, you’ll fling them out. And do it quickly.
I want to talk about killing our much beloved side-projects, and why this is totally a good idea. Then I want to talk about why this could be a terrible idea. I’m not here for resolutions.
There are two parts of my personality, plucked from the universe-scale D&amp;amp;D Players Manual, which make the question “should I carry on with this side project?</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #37</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-24-things-i-learned-37/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-24-things-i-learned-37/</guid><description>This week I’ve been focusing on perspective and gratitude. It’s harder than it sounds if you feel things are unfair and not in your favour. But, to quote about a million throw cushions on Pinterest: you can’t control life, only how you react to it. So this week I am choosing to react by being grateful. Even if it has to start out feeling like a very pointed lie, or jibe to my less patient self.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #36</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-08-11-things-i-learned-36/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-08-11-things-i-learned-36/</guid><description>The cold snap in London is teasing us. Is it over? hopefully. But it will still be ~1C at night so don’t get too complacent. Still, the days already feel long. I can hardly remember it being dark at 4pm but I’m sure I’ll remember as soon as October comes. There’s a lot of spring, summer, and autumn between now and then though. Here’s some things I learned this week</description></item><item><title>Dash Cycle #01: (re)organising</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-12-dash-cycle-01-reorganising/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-12-dash-cycle-01-reorganising/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m building DashDot: a privacy-focused interval training app that doesn&amp;rsquo;t suck. The second cycle of development lasted March 15 - April 12. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at where we are.
Goals Here are the things I wanted to achieve in this cycle:
✅ Finalise the code architecture and restore tests ✅ Allow someone to complete a (timed) timer ✅ Focus on the persistence of timers and workouts. Make sure that relationships between these entities are persisted.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #35</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-08-11-things-i-learned-35/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-08-11-things-i-learned-35/</guid><description>The slightly cold-snap here in London continues. The optimistic sewing and sprouting that took place in my garden (such as it is in urban West London) have largely had to retreat to the comfort of the indoors. Covid-related deaths continue to fall in the UK, as we begin optimistically opening up after a very long winter. I’ve started to have more normal moments - more going into a (socially-distanced) office, going to (socially-distanced) gatherings of people outside of my household.</description></item><item><title>How much is just-enough system design for new apps and software?</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-08-just-enough-software-design/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-08-just-enough-software-design/</guid><description>I wrote this because of a paralysing problem in coding: how much should I design my new app’s architecture before I dive into code if I can only learn about my app’s architecture by coding it?
I’m building Dash Dot, an interval timer iOS app from scratch, and this is the problem I’ve been facing this month.
The temptation is to answer all possible questions about your app before you start coding it, but you have to resist.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #34</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-02-things-i-learned-34/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-04-02-things-i-learned-34/</guid><description>Things I Learned #34 We’ve made it to the Easter weekend. Spring has arrived here in London, which is to say it was 20 degrees C earlier this week and this morning it was 0, windy, and overcast. This time a year ago, my mental state was dominated by COVID-19 (something I barely even think about now), but that also lead me to notice the beauty of spring for the first time.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #33</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-26-things-i-learned-33/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-26-things-i-learned-33/</guid><description>This cassette revival: Last year&amp;rsquo;s (2020&amp;rsquo;s) sale of tape cassettes, the 90&amp;rsquo;s mainstay of car sound systems and OG Walkmans (Walkmen?) were the highest they have been since 2003. An increase of 94% on 2019. Despite having inferior sound quality to CDs and vinyl, the medium is a lot cheaper and easier to produce which means a lower initial investment and potentially higher profits, which is great for indie musicians.</description></item><item><title>Dash Cycle #00 - The Beginning</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-21-dash-cycle-00-the-beginning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-21-dash-cycle-00-the-beginning/</guid><description>Hello. I&amp;rsquo;m building an app called Dash Dot, it&amp;rsquo;s a native iOS app for interval training that is a) well-designed, and b) privacy- and utility-focused. This post covers the first (approx.) six weeks in designing and building the app.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never made a truly native app before (I have written things in React Native before, though), nor have I ever successfully released a product to the world. Maybe this will be the time 🤷‍♀️</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #32</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-20-things-i-learned-32/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-20-things-i-learned-32/</guid><description>Following on from International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day last week, news of Sarah Everard&amp;rsquo;s body being discovered broke on the 10th of March, a week after she went missing from Clapham, London. There have been subsequent vigils (and protests) to remind us all that violent and sexual crimes against women are under-reported and under-convicted, and that any fair and just society needs to build systems that don&amp;rsquo;t let people think (let alone know) that they can hurt or sexually assault another person and probably get away with it.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #31</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-13-things-i-learned-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-13-things-i-learned-31/</guid><description>This week we celebrated International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day. My love and support goes out to anyone who identifies with that label. Let&amp;rsquo;s keep pushing for fair representation and pay, acknowledgement of domestic labour as work, and maybe some systemic government-backed support for domestic abuse victims and sex workers that doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve the police where it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary. Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s a funny a bit by Iliza Shlesinger that I love.
This hijab-wearing model: Halima Aden is a Somali-American model who first came into popular attention, aged 19, in 2017 when she walked at an event for Kanye West&amp;rsquo;s Yeezy brand.</description></item><item><title>The Frustrating Mismatch of Design by User Journey but Build with Components</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-06-design-workflow-build-components/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-06-design-workflow-build-components/</guid><description>How do you design a good app?
It&amp;rsquo;s a charmingly amateurish question, but I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past five years primarily trying to design and build web apps and I don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer.
I regularly get sick of looking at my current and old designs and ask &amp;ldquo;why don&amp;rsquo;t these look like a competent adult made them, and can I make them actually good?&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ll typically then do two things:</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #30</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-03-things-i-learned-30/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-03-03-things-i-learned-30/</guid><description>These no longer fictional bridges: You know the bridges on the Euro notes? There are seven of them total (notes and bridges) which represent seven different architectural styles. They were originally designed in 2002 and were (at the time) fictitious bridges which didn&amp;rsquo;t exist anywhere - so that no country felt special or left out. Robin Stam, an architect from the Netherlands, has gone ahead and designed and built them all irl, for cyclists to use.</description></item><item><title>How to run Xcode tests for a SwiftUI iOS codebase with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-27-github-actions-xcode-tests/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-27-github-actions-xcode-tests/</guid><description>Tl;dr
Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve got a repo on GitHub. Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve got at least one set of tests in your Xcode codebase. Create the file below in yourproject/.github/workflows/main.yml: Replace the yourprojects and YourProjects with your file name git add .github/workflows/main.yml &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git commit -m &amp;quot;Add test GitHub action&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git push # Run My App&amp;#39;s tests whenever someone pushes to `main` or creates a PR into `main` name: CI on: # Triggers the workflow on push or pull request events but only for the main branch.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #29</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-26-things-i-learned-29/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-26-things-i-learned-29/</guid><description>This lineage of cats: Chartwell House, in Kent, England, was the home of Winston Churchill. It&amp;rsquo;s now owned and operated by the National Trust, a British institution, allowing visitors to see the gardens and houses. During Churchill&amp;rsquo;s life, he had a marmalade (white and ginger) cat, called Jock. A few months after Chartwell House was handed over to the National Trust by the Churchill family, the family made the request that there always be a marmalade cat with a white bib and four ginger paws.</description></item><item><title>Opinions from 48hr on Clubhouse</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-02-20-opinions-from-48hr-on-clubhouse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-02-20-opinions-from-48hr-on-clubhouse/</guid><description>Clubhouse is a new audio social network platform for iOS. It&amp;rsquo;s basically like having a moderated voice-only Zoom call. The entire network is largely three entities:
Users: Human beings who use the app. Clubhouse have taken a pretty hard line on non-human (e.g. business) accounts. Rooms: Pre-scheduled or impromptu virtual rooms that users can go in. Rooms are where the conversation happens. Only users on the stage can speak to the room.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #28</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-19-things-i-learned-28/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-19-things-i-learned-28/</guid><description>This collective noun: If I was to make a list of small-talk and first date conversation topics it would go something like this: food, the tube, podcasts or books, and then collective nouns for animals. How many times have I been told the words &amp;ldquo;a parliament of owls&amp;rdquo; in my life? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, but I love re-remembering every time. This week I learned a new collective noun, and I&amp;rsquo;m sorry if you heard this one already: a scurry of squirrels.</description></item><item><title>Swift Closures: Inline functions explained by a web developer</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-17-closures-in-swift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-17-closures-in-swift/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Thomas. I&amp;rsquo;m a frontend engineer who&amp;rsquo;s learning swift. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about closures in Swift from a very (very) introductory level. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming you&amp;rsquo;ve got some familiarity with JavaScript. You should definitely check out Apple&amp;rsquo;s documentation on Closures, it&amp;rsquo;s so much better than this page but also, like, less funny?
Closures are inline function definitions.
We have inline functions all over the place in JavaScript. Callback functions, including those in promises, are often declared in JavaScript:</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #27</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-13-things-i-learned-27/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-13-things-i-learned-27/</guid><description>This seventeenth century petition: In 1674 in England, a pamphlet was made and published, titled The Women&amp;rsquo;s Petition Against Coffee. The women (or alleged women, we don&amp;rsquo;t actually know who wrote this) were fighting against the new trend of coffee houses in London, which had arrived some time in the 1650s. These proto-cafés became political and intellectual hubs in London, just as they had in other parts of the world, where men would meet and discuss all sorts of dangerous things like politics and science.</description></item><item><title>Website Design 2.0 Changelog</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-12-website-design-2-0-changelog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-12-website-design-2-0-changelog/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve redesigned the blog. This post just covers the technical whats and hows of it all.
What&amp;rsquo;s changed ? New Dark theme colours: Look around. Look at this dark purply-grey. Look at the same brand-orange, and the deliciously crisp white text. New colours! 100% More Portfolio: I completely revamped the homepage so that it actually showcases my writing and my work. The content isn&amp;rsquo;t hidden behind anything anymore. 50% Less Bio: I&amp;rsquo;ve shortened bios and text on the home page, they made the site feel a lot more static and like a placeholder site than I wanted.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #26</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-06-things-i-learned-26/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-02-06-things-i-learned-26/</guid><description>This heartening fact: Altruism, more specifically altruistic behaviour, is an action done (at cost) by an individual for the benefit of another individual. Why do humans, and other social animals, engage in altruistic behaviour? How does it makes sense on the evolutionary balance sheets? There is increasing evidence that altruism is an evolved, or more specifically phylogenetic, behaviour and that it is not learned. As social creatures, humans have an innate ability to empathise with each other.</description></item><item><title>Tiny Thought: Frontend Engineering is a Fullstack Problem</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-31-frontend-is-fullstack/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-31-frontend-is-fullstack/</guid><description>Tiny Thoughts are little (&amp;lt;500 word) essays. They&amp;rsquo;re concise.
Hypothesis: Frontend engineering cannot exist in isolation from backend technologies.
What sparked this: Thinking about building the next generation of web software at Oxwash.
All software is either&amp;hellip;
Used by a human for a human-scale (i.e. nebulous and larger) task like updating a status on social media, download a bank statement, or send a message. Used by other software to complete some computer-scale (i.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #25</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-29-things-i-learned-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-29-things-i-learned-25/</guid><description>This etymology: The word &amp;ldquo;peculiar&amp;rdquo; has come to mean odd or unique, so obviously its Latin root word (‌peculium) means somebody&amp;rsquo;s cattle. Cows were pretty valuable assets back in the day: you can eat them, milk them, use them as work animals, so they became a symbol of wealth. Later, ‌peculiaris evolved from this same root word to mean &amp;ldquo;of private property&amp;rdquo;, i.e. belonging to one person. This link makes sense too - if cattle are the stereotypical idea of property and wealth, then they&amp;rsquo;ll start to become synonymous.</description></item><item><title>My Top Albums of 2020</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-27-top-albums-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-27-top-albums-2020/</guid><description>Just a quick blog post to highlight that I&amp;rsquo;ve published my 2020 Top Albums of the Year. You can find it here. Seriously, go check it out.
I really enjoy making little specially art-directed pages like this. It feels very &amp;ldquo;this is what the internet was made for&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s just a quirky little bespoke designed page which oozes my love for music. No tracking, no adverts, just a quirky font and cool colour scheme.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #24</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-23-things-i-learned-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-23-things-i-learned-24/</guid><description>This fitness research: I&amp;rsquo;ve long been a fan of interval training to help improve my running and cycling speed. High intensity interval training (HIIT) is a method of training where you mix short bursts of intense activity (e.g. a 30 second sprint) between longer periods of low-intensity exercise (e.g. 90 seconds slow jog). It&amp;rsquo;s time-efficient, evidence-backed, and makes me uncomfortably sweaty so it must be good. Our current guess is that by pushing through into very high intensity activity you trigger different physiological responses, compared to sustained moderate exercise.</description></item><item><title>Design Resource: Free Fonts from Awwwards (2021)</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/design-resource-free-fonts-from-awwwards/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/design-resource-free-fonts-from-awwwards/</guid><description>Awwwards have put out a collection of free (or free-adjacent) fonts. You can find them here.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #23</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-15-things-i-learned-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-15-things-i-learned-23/</guid><description>These underwater drawings: Go back to 1860s and ask someone what coral reefs, or fish, or literally any marine life looked like. Go on. I bet they&amp;rsquo;d tell you they had no idea. How would they? Sure, we&amp;rsquo;d been sending people down there since the 1500s in these giant metal bells but those were more function-over-form. You couldn&amp;rsquo;t really see out of them. Around the 1400s we maybe started sending people down with metal crates over their head and tubes attached to their suits to feed air to them.</description></item><item><title>An ode to note taking with markdown files</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-10-an-ode-to-plaintext-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-10-an-ode-to-plaintext-notes/</guid><description>This is based off a sesh (think lightning talk, but&amp;hellip; cooler?) I gave at Oxwash, where I am a frontend software engineer. I wanted to give an overview for how I take notes in pretty much every area of my life, including my job but also for holidays, notes from books I am reading, and for writing posts like this.
Over the past twelve months my thinking has converged towards the idea that plaintext files (like Markdown) are a great choice for note making and keeping.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #22</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-09-things-i-learned-22/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-09-things-i-learned-22/</guid><description>This week the UK Government has brought us Lockdown The Third, a threequel in the franchise after the straight-to-TV movie that was the November lockdown. Cases, deaths, and hospital admissions are at an all-time high in our country at the moment, with London in particular looking pretty scary. It might be the &amp;ldquo;the last push&amp;rdquo; like this (boy, I really hope it is the last push), but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t help the healthcare workers being forced forward/backwards/downwards by this whole situation.</description></item><item><title>2021 Theme: The Year of Discourse</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-02-yearly-theme-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-02-yearly-theme-2021/</guid><description>Resolutions are dumb. They&amp;rsquo;re unsustainable and you can fail at them. Humans are just awful at long-term behaviour or thought-pattern change. Instead, I like themes: broad ideas that only try to guide you, not dictate. They&amp;rsquo;re not a single thing, they&amp;rsquo;re like a north star, or a prompt for conversation and reflection when you pause for it. CGP Grey condensed his thoughts on them into a neat little six-minute video. If you&amp;rsquo;re more into it, or like podcasts, here&amp;rsquo;s an episode of Cortex to listen to.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #21</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-01-things-i-learned-21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-01-01-things-i-learned-21/</guid><description>Happy New Year 🎊🥳🍾 It&amp;rsquo;s been one hell of a ride, 2020, and I hope that I never know another year like you. This has been quite enough. We&amp;rsquo;re at least six months from being slightly out of the woods, but we&amp;rsquo;ve made it through nine-to-twelve (depending on where you live) months of surprise pandemic. We can make it through another six. I don&amp;rsquo;t care that 365 days or a rotation around the sun is arbitrary.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #20</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-27-things-i-learned-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-27-things-i-learned-20/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s post comes a little lighter, on account of it being Christmas and all. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to break a streak, but also I want to get back to eating far too much and doing far too little. So let&amp;rsquo;s get on with it:
This etymology: The word apocalypse comes from the Greek apokaluptein: to uncover, or reveal. This original meaning got adopted in bible translations in the context of revelations - which makes sense.</description></item><item><title>How are we going to write about 2020 from 2022 onwards?</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-20-how-are-we-going-to-write-about-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-20-how-are-we-going-to-write-about-2020/</guid><description>2020 has been a terrible year in so, so many ways for so, so many people. At the very least, the Covid-19 pandemic has stolen a year from us all. I would say most of us have gone through a personal and collective trauma this year.
I do not believe this year will be a turning point for us as a society. I don&amp;rsquo;t think this will be the moment people stopped flying transatlantic for a 2pm lunch meeting in LA.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #19</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-18-things-i-learned-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-18-things-i-learned-19/</guid><description>All of these species named after David Attenborough: The man&amp;rsquo;s a living legend (he&amp;rsquo;s also like 94 - he was a teenager in the 1930s which was before the second world war - this isn&amp;rsquo;t the fact by the way, this is just some incredible side-facts). The collective scientific community has named over 20 species of animals and plants after him, including Attenborosaurus - the marine dinosaur, Pristimantis attenborough - a Peruvian frog, and Acisoma attenboroughi - a dragonfly.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #18</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-11-things-i-learned-18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-11-things-i-learned-18/</guid><description>I took a four day week last week, so managed to spend this week with all the energy that only a 3-day weekend can give you. That said, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself incredibly busy this week. This is the first evening (Thursday) where I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to find some time to myself without something pressing. Lockdown continues, Brexit talks and COVID vaccine are competing for media attention, but also I bought two (2!</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #17</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-05-things-i-learned-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-12-05-things-i-learned-17/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s time of year again: Spotify have released their Rewind - showing you what you listened to throughout this year. After the year (or decade, or complete non-year, whatever helps you) that 2020 has been, I think a lot of people have looked to music for a bit of refuge, or good news, or distraction. Go and check yours out, it&amp;rsquo;s a cool little use of data, presented in a really nice way.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #16</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-27-things-i-learned-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-27-things-i-learned-16/</guid><description>These Tattoos: In the late 1880s, a man called Sutherland Macdonald became the UK&amp;rsquo;s first professioanl tattoo artist. Although he was already an artist, he started the tattoo craft after a trip to the South Pacific. Macdonald is the reason we have the word &amp;lsquo;tattooist&amp;rsquo; (a portmanteau of tattoo and artist) - because the Post Office had to create a new category to place an advert for his services in.</description></item><item><title>Tiny thought: On the separation of design and engineering</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-23-on-the-separation-of-design-and-engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-23-on-the-separation-of-design-and-engineering/</guid><description>Tiny Thoughts are little (&amp;lt;500 word) essays. They&amp;rsquo;re concise.
I make user interfaces, and I often participate in, or lead, the process of designing these interfaces. For a while I thought I wanted to transition fully into a design role. Ultimately I am drawn to the certainty and craft of engineering. However, the the mental models, sensibilities, and philosophies of design still appeal to me. I can like both, and businesses need both.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #15</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-20-things-i-learned-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-20-things-i-learned-15/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t it getting dark early ?&amp;rdquo; - how I&amp;rsquo;ve started at least half of the conversations I&amp;rsquo;ve had this week.
This thing that spreads like a disease: Look, I was a germaphobe before it was cool. I was very aware of how one thing can spread from person to person. However this contagious model of disease doesn&amp;rsquo;t just apply to problems caused by bacteria/virus/any other vectors. Obesity can spread like disease, where if your friendships mostly comprise of obese people who normalise a sedentary lifestyle, or poor diet, you&amp;rsquo;re nearly about 170% more likely to be obese than if you weren&amp;rsquo;t in these friendships.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Figma Variants with 5 Components that aren't Buttons</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-19-figma-variants-without-buttons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-19-figma-variants-without-buttons/</guid><description>Figma recently introduced Variants - a way of extending and varying your components. Components in Figma, and in modern web development, are reusable and encapsulated elements of a design - with the classic examples of a Button or a Card.
Variants add new flexibility, and utility, to components in Figma by introducing properties and values to them in a programmatic way. If you have experience writing modern web applications, these variants and properties are like a specific subset of props which you pass to a component.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #14</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-13-things-i-learned-14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-13-things-i-learned-14/</guid><description>Happy Friday 13th. I hope it&amp;rsquo;s spooky and magical.
This Roman Beverage: I&amp;rsquo;d imagine the Romans were pretty thirsty. The Mediterranean is warm, and you&amp;rsquo;d work up quite the thirst inventing a whole number system, apartments, a calendar, and like a million kinds of war machinery. Not that I&amp;rsquo;d know. The Romans bloody loved posca: a mix of vinegar and water (or diluted wine), seasoned with herbs and salt. It was incredibly popular in both the military and with citizenry an.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #13</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-07-things-i-learned-13/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-07-things-i-learned-13/</guid><description>WHAT. A. WEEK. It feels the entire western world has had their eyes on the US presidential election, and it&amp;rsquo;s been exhausting. Not exhausting in the way that the last 12 months have been for the US, but exhausting in the way that nothing in 2020 has lead us to expect anything good to happen. As I write this, Joe Biden and Kamala Harris have just been elected as president- and vice president-elect.</description></item><item><title>Why are you like this JavaScript? JavaScript Runtimes and Engines</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-01-js-runtimes-and-engines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-11-01-js-runtimes-and-engines/</guid><description>Sometimes you keep hearing words but you&amp;rsquo;re not actually sure what they mean, but you&amp;rsquo;re too afraid to ask and keep forgetting to Google it. For me, two of those phrases have been &amp;ldquo;JavaScript runtime&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;JavaScript engine&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve never studied Comp Sci at uni, and I&amp;rsquo;ve never practically needed to be able to define either of them.
If that sounds similar to you, then buckle up cowboys and cowgirls because you&amp;rsquo;re about to go &amp;ldquo;oh, yeah, cool&amp;rdquo; a lot at some pretty basic distinctions that you probably intuitively knew but didn&amp;rsquo;t have the words for.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #12</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-31-things-i-learned-12/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-31-things-i-learned-12/</guid><description>This high fat diet: Whales, like dolphins but also humans, are mammals. This means they feed their young with milk. As you would expect, the blue whale has the largest mammary glands on Earth – each is about 1.5m long and weighs as much as a baby elephant. Blue whale mothers can produce 200 litres of milk per day, with a fat content of 35-50%. For reference, double cream is about 48% fat.</description></item><item><title>Tiny thought: Writing for recipe cards</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-24-writing-for-recipe-cards/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-24-writing-for-recipe-cards/</guid><description>Tiny Thoughts are little (&amp;lt;500 word) essays. They&amp;rsquo;re concise.
I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past three months consciously trying to write and read more. I want to improve my ability to refine and communicate thought, and doing it in public helps motivate me to produce work.
One of the hardest problems I find myself addressing frequently is my desire to over-explain or provide too much information. I have read many times that good writing is about being concise.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #11</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-23-things-i-learned-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-23-things-i-learned-11/</guid><description>This thing about how we sleep: In Western Europe, about 35% of young adults sleep with a soft toy every night, and about 44% of people keep hold of their childhood soft toy. It can be especially helpful for people with low self-esteem, or higher anxiety to sleep with a soft toy, apparently. As someone who&amp;rsquo;s kept firm tabs on their childhood bear (though I&amp;rsquo;d say we sleep adjacent, not together), it shocks me that over half of people would throw their teddybear away.</description></item><item><title>Think in Frameworks, build with Libraries - Thinking about CSS in Web Development</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-20-mental-frameworks-in-design-engineering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-20-mental-frameworks-in-design-engineering/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a few weeks into starting a new job as a frontend software engineer, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been moving around our (Angular) codebases to make a few smaller changes, and bump a number of our core dependencies through a couple of major (e.g. 1.0.0 -&amp;gt; 2.0.0) versions.
This caused a few visual changes, and in fixing, or at least understanding, what&amp;rsquo;s happened I was rooting around a lot of the component-scoped style files (which are SASS files).</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #10</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-16-things-i-learned-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-16-things-i-learned-10/</guid><description>This Tiny City: St. David&amp;rsquo;s is a city with a population of about 1,000 people. In 1886 it was stripped of its status as a city, being described as &amp;ldquo;lonely, and the neighbouring district wild and unimproved&amp;rdquo;. In 1994 Queen Elizabeth II requested it be restored as a city, and now it is. (source) This Terrible Surgeon: In the 1800s Robert Liston, a London-based surgeon, was famous for performing amputations quickly.</description></item><item><title>Five (and a bit) useful questions to answer in your first week at a new job</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-10-five-useful-questions-new-job/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-10-five-useful-questions-new-job/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just had my first week at a new job (I&amp;rsquo;m now a frontend software engineer at Oxwash), which is cool. I find first weeks intense because I have to balance a) the immediacy of being introduced to everything and everyone in &amp;ldquo;real life&amp;rdquo;, i.e. not an interview setting, for the first time, and b) trying to convey your long-term personal and professional ambitions to your new bosses without sounding like a career lunatic or emotionless psychopath.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #9 (Nobel Prize edition)</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-09-things-i-learned-9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-09-things-i-learned-9/</guid><description>In honour of the announcement of (some of) the 2020 Nobel Prizes, this week&amp;rsquo;s edition contains entirely things I learned when reading about the people and work announced so far. Note that this doesn&amp;rsquo;t include anything about the Peace or Economics prizes, which had not been announced at the time of writing.
I also started a new job this week so I&amp;rsquo;m running at 5-10% mental capacity so we&amp;rsquo;re in for another short edition this week!</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #8</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-02-things-i-learned-8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-10-02-things-i-learned-8/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s Things I learned is a little shorter than usual because I&amp;rsquo;ve been moving house. I hate every part of moving house. Anyway, enough excuses, here are some of the things I learned this week:
This thing about reading: I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about how much we read recently. I think we&amp;rsquo;d all like to read more, and you hear so often of speed readers who can devour books in hours.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering as a Craft</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-28-software-engineering-as-a-craft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-28-software-engineering-as-a-craft/</guid><description>A few months ago a prominent figure in the tech and software space was uninvited from a conference1. In an (intentionally humorous) summary of this person, Melissa McEwan wrote a Tech Bullshit Explained about the person. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about any of allegations or (tellingly-immature) reactions to the allegations, but something McEwan said in her post didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to fit, and to me seemed a little too far. She says:</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #7</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-25-things-i-learned-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-25-things-i-learned-7/</guid><description>This unknown origin: No one is quite certain where the term &amp;ldquo;rule of thumb&amp;rdquo; came from. It has been mistakenly attributed to a British Judge&amp;rsquo;s rule that a man can beat his wife if the stick so long as it is less wide than his thumb, however there&amp;rsquo;s no evidence to support that this ruling was ever made. (source) This heist: The police recently seized about £2.5m worth of books which were originally stolen in 2017.</description></item><item><title>My experience finding a new job as a software engineer in summer of 2020</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-20-interviewing-experience-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-20-interviewing-experience-2020/</guid><description>In late summer of 2020 I moved from freelance software engineer to a full-time position. I want to outline this process for literally anybody who&amp;rsquo;s interested because I&amp;rsquo;ve found it useful when other people have done the same - like this post about interviewing at Google, this front-end, and this more generic post.
Web development is a joyfully open community. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of sharing, most often we share code, but we also share details about the wider context of our field.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #6</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-18-things-i-learned-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-18-things-i-learned-6/</guid><description>These ways of thinking: When we hand over a new problem to our brain there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of things we need to do to solve it. We need to understand the problem and the surrounding/causal concepts as well as the constraints on a solution. For example the challenge might be &amp;ldquo;what should I write about on my blog this week?&amp;rdquo;, and a constraint might be that it a) can&amp;rsquo;t be boring, and b) can&amp;rsquo;t be too long.</description></item><item><title>Things I Learned this week #5</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-11-things-i-learned-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-11-things-i-learned-5/</guid><description>This missed opportunity to name something: Ping Pong is a weird name for a sport, right? Ping Pong is actually a trademarked name, but it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to call a thing by a brand name: it&amp;rsquo;s like Hoover vs. Vacuum Cleaner, or Kleenex vs. Tissue. The real-fun fact here is that in 1900 Slazenger, a sports company, filed a trademark for the term Whiff-Waff - and 120 years laters (somehow) Ping Pong prevailed while Whiff-Waff died out, despite the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s clearly more joyful.</description></item><item><title>Why are you like this, JavaScript? An introduction to Promises by using Fetch.</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-06-javascript-promises-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-06-javascript-promises-introduction/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a correct, but pretty dense, definition: JavaScript Promises are a first-class abstraction for handling asynchronous actions, like:
Fetching data from a remote API. Reading or writing (i.e. opening or saving) a file to the filesystem (in a server-side environment, not in a browser). Retrieving a non-blurred-up version of an image based on a page-scroll event. Using network or system utilities in native mobile frameworks like react-native or expo.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #4</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-04-things-i-learned-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-09-04-things-i-learned-4/</guid><description>This world: The Word Kipple is a word invented by SciFi writer Phillip K. Dick, to mean the kind of rubbish/trash that accumulates if humans don&amp;rsquo;t intervene. source This part of our brain: You know when you suddenly remember that you need to reply to that e-mail, drop off that parcel, or pick up eggs before dinner? That&amp;rsquo;s your prospective memory - which is kind of the opposite of your normal memory (your retrospective memory) because it &amp;ldquo;remembers&amp;rdquo; things which need to happen in the future.</description></item><item><title>Apple, What are you doing?</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-29-apple-what-are-you-doing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-29-apple-what-are-you-doing/</guid><description>I have loved Apple solidly for eight years, since I was 20 and gifted a Mac Mini for Christmas. I wrote my Masters thesis on that thing in a ground floor bedroom of a student house overlooking suburbia at 3am on a Tuesday night. I finished my Ph.D. thesis on a MacBook Air (which certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t deserve to be put through what I asked it to do) as I sat, hunched over, on a rainy November afternoon, in a tiny flat in Paris that smelled like fresh lemon and ginger.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #3</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-21-things-i-learned-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-21-things-i-learned-3/</guid><description>This medieval lingo: Have you ever wondered how to refer to the area where a good-old-fashioned joust took place? You know, jousts? Two men, two horses, two giant poles, and one film where Heath Ledger is irresponsibly handsome? Sorry, I got distracted there - did you know the area where the jousts took places is called a List, and the fence that separated the two riders is called the Tilt (source).</description></item><item><title>Why are you like this, JavaScript? Taking a look at JavaScript's single threaded nature.</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-23-why-are-you-like-this-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-23-why-are-you-like-this-javascript/</guid><description>Sometimes you hear something so often that you don&amp;rsquo;t really hear it anymore. One of those things for me is words to the effect of &amp;ldquo;How does this JavaScript code even run?&amp;rdquo;. I choose to interpret this generously as &amp;ldquo;How does JavaScript itself run&amp;rdquo;, and not &amp;ldquo;how does this hot garbage code you wrote run?&amp;rdquo;.[^I really hope I don&amp;rsquo;t write as much hot garbage JavaScript as I used to]
There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of ways we could describe JavaScript (including some really colourful adjectives), but objectively it is an asynchronous, single-threaded, dynamic programming language.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #2</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-21-things-i-learned-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-21-things-i-learned-2/</guid><description>This useful thinking tool: good writing starts with observations, and moves to analysis. Making the transition is difficult. One way to spot a mental crutch is to see where you reach for words like &amp;ldquo;interestingly&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;surprisingly&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;notably&amp;rdquo;. These all hint at a significance or meaningfulness, but don&amp;rsquo;t actually clarify it. (source) This hot takeaway: Did you know that during the 1970s if you ordered a takeaway coffee it came in a styrofoam cup and a lid without a hole.</description></item><item><title>Things I learned this week #1</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-14-things-i-learned-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-14-things-i-learned-1/</guid><description>This tidbit about a literary villa: Over three days in June of 1816 at a villa in Geneva, Mary Shelley started writing Frankenstein, or The Modern Prometheus and John William Polidori started The Vampyre (which preceded the modern romantic image of vampires). The latter inspired Lord Byron (who was also at the villa, by the way) to write A Fragment. Imagine being 2am whiskey drunk at that, wow. This way to think about css/styling: The decisions we make about the naming, structure, and languages/frameworks for modern styling tools just move complexity, they don’t solve it.</description></item><item><title>Where I go for UI inspiration</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-07-where-i-go-for-ui-inspiration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-08-07-where-i-go-for-ui-inspiration/</guid><description>Like anybody who makes interfaces for apps/websites, I spent a lot of time looking at Design Inspiration (read: UIs, real or imaginary, made by other people). This is a really good way to look at visual conventions that other people made, and have used in their UIs and UX.
If I were to examine the time I spent “designing” more closely, and divided it between actually pushing pixels around in Figma, and looking at other people’s work on Dribbble I would be shocked and ashamed.</description></item><item><title>Deploying an MVP Rails App with Render like it's 2020</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-06-11-deploy-rails-in-render/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-06-11-deploy-rails-in-render/</guid><description>📚tl;dr - I used Render to deploy a Rails app and database. It was very easy, very fast, and very modern. Would recommend to everyone.
Way back before the pandemic I had the idea for hereabouts - an app that people can use to explore the city they&amp;rsquo;re visiting, or live in. After making a landing page, working hard to build a lot of UI and UX prototypes, and beginning the process of emerging from national and international lockdown from a pandemic, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to come to the part where I build out a backend API - to store data, largely.</description></item><item><title>I don't want to be a unicorn 🦄, an engineer or a designer - I just want to build things better</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-05-31-unicorns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-05-31-unicorns/</guid><description>I like building software, or parts of software, which are visual and interactive. I do not particularly enjoy the more abstract, very important, areas like technical optimisation, language design, or anything with the word &amp;ldquo;distributed&amp;rdquo; in it. I like building user interfaces (UIs); but also architecting and engineering the code that underlies these interfaces, so that engineers can build delightful and functional UIs, without going through as much effort. Good UI and user experience (UX) should be a norm, a default.</description></item><item><title>Hereabouts devblog #2 - March 2020</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-04-02-hereabouts-devblog-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-04-02-hereabouts-devblog-2/</guid><description>Hi, I’m Thomas Wilson, I’m a web and mobile engineer building Hereabouts - an app that’s like a tour guide if the tour guide was like Roman Mars after three beers. This is a devblog where I talk about my progress building that app. Also I’m very sorry, Roman, you’re one of a handful of people who I genuinely aspire to be like please don’t take me seriously.
Well March 2020 has certainly turned out to be quite the introduction to working on a side project.</description></item><item><title>Why I chose React Native to build a new app in 2020</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-03-22-why-i-chose-react-native-for-app-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-03-22-why-i-chose-react-native-for-app-in-2020/</guid><description>I am currently in the process of building herabouts - an app that’s like a tour guide, only cooler. Most of my previous engineering work has been web-based (react and vue) because the internet is an accessible and very capable system for building modern applications. However hereabouts needed certain native functionality - like location, reliable offline data access, battery status, and access to the camera. Yes some of these things are possible on the web, but they’re much more native functionality.</description></item><item><title>Kickstarting UX Design with ugly working documents: Screens, Components, Actions, and State.</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-03-15-ugly-but-functional-ux-design/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-03-15-ugly-but-functional-ux-design/</guid><description>UX design resists standardisation or templates. It can’t be a one-size-fits-all approach, and the nature of the product, audience, and production team all mean that something different is needed each time. Whenever I get past the early stages of UX design (like understanding what a product does, and who it does it for) - I find myself with a different working document and process than I’ve needed before.
I wanted to share the things I do that give me the momentum to get to a place where I can do this more specific kind of document.</description></item><item><title>Hereabouts devblog #1</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-02-24-hereabouts-devblog-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2020-02-24-hereabouts-devblog-1/</guid><description>Hi, my name’s Thomas Wilson but I often go by my just my surname. I’m 28 years old, currently based in London, England, and I design and build software for a living through my small independent studio tinyfox studio. At the beginning of 2020 I quit my job to do this independently, and now I’m building hereabouts - an app that provides self-paced walks, tours, hunts, and races for travel adventurers In this devblog series I want to record to the process of building something modern and beautiful from the ground up.</description></item><item><title>Re-publishing my writing on my experiences with food and eating disorders</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/introducing-eating-anthology/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/introducing-eating-anthology/</guid><description>tl;dr - I have moved the writing I have created on my experiences with eating disorders to this site (and off of Medium.). You can find them here.
For at least the past five years, my mental health has been affected through and alongside a weird relationship with food, exercise, and eating. I find writing helps me clarify my thoughts and my situation to me. While a lot of this writing is intentionally private, there are a couple of piece I want to be publicly available.</description></item><item><title>Moving my personal site to Gatsby</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/moving-from-nuxt-to-gatsbyjs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/moving-from-nuxt-to-gatsbyjs/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I was having a conversation with someone about modern web design, and we spoke about web fonts and variable fonts. In my experience, people who work in software development have a couple of hills that they will die on, if so required. For this person - the idea of not using system fonts (i.e. typefaces which are already installed on a user’s device) was completely baffling. Why are we increasing the time-to-load and packet size required to display a web page - just for a typeface.</description></item><item><title>Culture I devoured in Autumn 2019</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/culture-i-devoured-autumn-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/culture-i-devoured-autumn-2019/</guid><description>This season turned out to be surprisingly busy with culture. I started the month by talking at two tech events in London, meaning I arrived into the full body of the month having produced some very technical, thoughtful output. I needed some really well-considered and curated culture to put everything back in the right places. Kind of like an internal tidy-up after I’d rummaged through all of my draws to produce someone who was definitely more knowledgeable than I am, and probably a lot funnier and more extroverted.</description></item><item><title>What is CSS-in-JS and why do people keep using it?</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/what-and-why-use-css-in-js/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/what-and-why-use-css-in-js/</guid><description>The elders tell us of a time where you would build websites by literally writing your .html files. If you wanted to add some styles, you’d write them in a .css file and then &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot;&amp;gt; the two together. So you’d write your entire site in semantic HTML, about whatever it is people did back then (like mammoth hunting or pyramid building) and then you would ftp that onto your server, and other people could view it.</description></item><item><title>Back to Bear, Goodbye Notion</title><link>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/back-to-bear/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thomaswilson.xyz/blog/back-to-bear/</guid><description>This piece turned out a little long than expected because I really want to clarify that this is not a “Why Bear is better than Notion” article. It is a “Why Bear suits my needs right now better than Notion” discussion. So there’s a little more nuance in my explanation. The crux of my point it is this: I am a scatter brained person who develops software, makes dance, and exercises semi-seriously - and I need a digital tool to help me manage my thoughts, writing, documentation, and general projects.</description></item></channel></rss>