<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>weekly on Thomas Wilson</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/tags/weekly/</link><description>Recent content in weekly on Thomas Wilson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>© Thomas Wilson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 08:40:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/tags/weekly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Weekly #45: This is an old story</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-27-weekly-45-this-is-an-old-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 08:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-27-weekly-45-this-is-an-old-story/</guid><description>The Weekly is a series of essays where I write on something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about over the last seven days. They&amp;rsquo;re under a thousand words. There&amp;rsquo;s some stuff going on in my professional life (positive stuff, but still stuff, you know?) so it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a short one this week. It&amp;rsquo;s better to publish than not.
I want to talk about old stories. I mean things that people have been experiencing for thousands or tens or thousands of years.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #44: Thinking about Conspiracy Theories</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-10-weekly-44-thinking-about-conspiracy-theories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-10-weekly-44-thinking-about-conspiracy-theories/</guid><description>The Weekly is a series of essays under one thousand words where I write about something I’ve been thinking over the last seven days. This week I want to talk about misinformation and conspiracy theories surrounding Covid-19, and why they’re more harmful than previous conspiracy theories. I’ve been a little busier than usual this week, so let’s get into it
Alongside the actual pandemic of Covid-19, the World Health Organisation (WHO) has declared an infodemic: the “false or misleading information in digital and physical environments during a disease outbreak”.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #43: Vision, problem, and action</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-05-weekly-43-vision-problem-action/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 10:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-06-05-weekly-43-vision-problem-action/</guid><description>The Weekly is a weekly essay where I write about something I’ve been thinking about in the last seven days. They’re under 1000 words, and this week I want to talk about vision and problems when you’re building a new product.
I’m building the lexicon, where I am (un-ironically) trying to build the world’s most useful language learning resources. I like Duo Lingo, but I don’t think it helps you much in the real world ™️.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #42: Metaphors for Design - Brutalist Architecture, Gardens, and Video Games</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-28-the-weekly-42-metaphors-for-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-28-the-weekly-42-metaphors-for-design/</guid><description>The Weekly is a weekly essay on something I’ve been thinking about in the last seven days. They’re less than a thousand words long. This week I want to talk about the metaphors we use when we talk about designing for the web.
I read two (fantastic) pieces on the web this week:
What even is a website anyway? by Manuel Moreale, who cited, Brutalist Web Design by Carl Barenbrug Sometimes I have no time for Medium-style self proclaimed “think pieces” about the web and technology.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #41: Productivity is a daily ritual</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-21-productivity-is-a-daily-ritual/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 20:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-21-productivity-is-a-daily-ritual/</guid><description>The Weekly is a 1000-word-or-less essay on something I’ve been thinking this week. Let’s talk about how productivity is (basically) a scam and how daily and weekly rituals are the backbone of any sane person&amp;rsquo;s productivity.
I once had the goal to move to Paris. I didn’t achieve it (there was a pandemic). I had a goal to learn Italian (laziness). We’ve all got visions of our future where we’re cleverer, skinnier, more intelligent, or in my case simply the same person but somewhere else.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #40: Garlic &amp; The Ancients</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-15-weekly-40/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-15-weekly-40/</guid><description>Okay let’s learn us how over the past 3000 years garlic has been espoused by healers and spiritual leaders to ward off disease and evil. It’ll take you down a rabbit hole of medical advice, social segregation, and spiritual prohibition.
Garlic (Allium Sativum, of theAllium genus) has set its roots deep in the human story. And let’s get one thing straight: garlic is bloody great. It’s scientifically categorised in a group of foods called “please don’t take these away from me”.</description></item><item><title>The Weekly #39 (or #1, whatever)</title><link>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-06-weekly-39/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thomaswilson.xyz/blog/2021-05-06-weekly-39/</guid><description>I’m going to stop writing my “things I learned” blog posts. They don’t serve me in the way that they used to. As I wrote recently: kill your ideas and side projects, gladly and without delay.
Death is more of a transition, though. The things I learned this week post is becoming simply _The Weekly.
I’m not sure what I’m going to use it to write about, I’m going to take a few weeks to try some new formats out.</description></item></channel></rss>